Register to The Isidor Achron Papers
Yale University Music Library
- Music, Series I
  - Music by Other Composers
    - [Habanera] Habanera., Souviron, Yvette; 1 score (3 p.); 32 cm. (Box 2, Folder 26)
      Begins in key of E minor.
      At end: Yvette Souviron, New York 1962
    - [Habanera] Habanera., Souviron, Yvette; 1 score (4 p.); 33 cm. (Box 2, Folder 26)
      Begins in key of G minor.
      At end: Yvette Souvirnon
    - [Habanera] Habanera., Souviron, Yvette; 1 score (4 p.); 33 cm. (Box 2, Folder 26)
      Manuscript and typescript lyrics.
      Begins in key of E-flat minor.
    - [Mélodie gitane] Mélodie gitane / Yvette Souviron., Souviron, Yvette; 1 score (2 p.); 37 cm. (Box 2, Folder 26)
      Spanish and French words.
      At end: Yvette Souviron, 1953
    - [Pardonne moi] "Pardonne moi"., Souviron, Yvette; 1 score (3 p.); 33 cm. (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - [Vidala] Vidala., Souviron, Yvette; 1 score (4 p.); 34 cm. (Box 2, Folder 26)
      Holograph with typescript, photocopy.
    - [Zigeunerbaron, arr.] Zigeunerbaron., Strauss, Johann; 1 score (2 p.) + 10 parts; 32 cm. (Box 2, Folder 27)
      For chamber orchestra.
      2 copies of score.
    - [Estro armonico. no. 11. Largo. arr.] Larghetto (from the concerto for string orchestra) Vivaldi-Heifetz. New York: C. Fischer, 1929., Vivaldi, Antonio, 1678-1741; 1 score (5 p.) + 1 part (1 p.); 31 cm. (Box 2, Folder 27)
      Plate no.: 25056-5
      Arr. for violin and piano by Jascha Heifetz.
    - [In April weather] "In April weather" / Bina Ethel Payne., Volper, Arnold; 1 score (4 p.); 31 cm. (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - [Sleep my child] Sleep my child., Unidentified; 1 score (3 p.); 32 cm. (Box 2, Folder 28)
      Manuscript with typescript lyrics.
      Text by Mme. Karina Tolstoy.
    - No title, first line of text: "love me, love the rich mermaid..."., Unidentified; 1 score (2 p.); 34 cm. (Box 2, Folder 28)
      Manuscript, photocopy.
    - Russian title, Unidentified; 1 score (3 p.); 32 cm (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - No title., Unidentified; 2 p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Correspondence of Isidor Achron and Lea Karina, Series II
  - American Red Cross, 1944-1946; 3 items (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Barbirolli, John & Evelyn, 1947-1970; 8 items (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Birdsall Publishers, Inc., 1936 Apr. 8; 1 item (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Castelnuovo-Tedesco, Mario & Clara, 19-- Christmas; 2 items (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Dagand, Henry, 1934 Jan. 8; 1 item (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Deis, Carl, 1946 Nov. 20; 1 item (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Engstrom, Sigrid W., 1936 Apr. 13; 1 item (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Fitzgeralds, Mr. & Mrs., 19-- Dec. 20; 1 item (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Fournier, Lyda, 19-- Christmas; 1 item (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Fund for the Relief of Men of Letters and Scientists of Russia, 1943 Dec. 4; 1 item (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Godowsky, Frances Gershwin, 1973 Sep. 10; 1 item (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Heifetz, Annie, 1922 Aug. 25; 3 items (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Heifetz, Florence, 1928 May --; 1 item (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Heifetz, Jascha, 1923 Mar 21; 1 item (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Heifetz, Jascha & Florence, 1928 Aug. 27; 1 item (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Heifetz, Jascha & Frances, 19-- Christmas; 3 items (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Hilliard, L., 1932 Jan. 3; 1 item (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Ives, Anice, 1935 Dec. 17; 1 item (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Judson, Arthur, 1941 Jan. 11; 1 item (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Klemetti, Heikki, 1939 June 21; 1 item (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Koussevitzky, Serge & Olga, no date; 3 items (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Leontovich, Eugenie, 1978-1979; 4 items (Box 3, Folder 30)
    2 items no date
  - Menuhin, Yehudi & Nola, 1941-1967; 7 items (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Moiseiwitsch, Mrs. B., 1948 Oct.28; 1 item (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Murray, Kathryn & Arthur, 19-- Christmas; 1 item (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Nyeacida, Leonard, 1949 Oct. 5; 1 item (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - National Screen Service, 1935 Jun. 3; 1 item (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Piatigorsky, J., no date; 1 item (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Peckham, A., 1947 Mar. 2; 1 item (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Ravitch, Helen, 1935 Feb. 4; 1 item (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Reuben, Arnold, 1945 Dec. 27; 1 item (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Rosen, Mrs. Walter T., no date; 1 item (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Sachs, Alexander, 1941 Jan. 12; 1 item (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Southern Illinois University, 1972-1974; 2 items (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Steinway, Theodore, 1941 Dec. 21; 2 items (Box 3, Folder 30)
    1 item no date
  - Steinway, William R., 1948 Apr. 6; 1 item (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Stokowski, Leopold, 1947 Jan. 16; 1 item (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Stoughton, A. G., 1936 Oct. 15; 1 item (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Swanson, Gloria, 19-- Christmas; 1 item (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Volpe, Arnold, 1939 Feb. 13; 1 item (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Werhart, Josephine, 19-- Mar. 29; 1 item (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Zunser, Mrs. Charles, 1937 Mar. 1; 1 item (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Unidentified correspondence, 1941-1974; 8 items (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Photographs, Series III
  - Isidor Achron alone
    - Isidor Achron alone, 1920-1929; photo# 1-7 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Isidor Achron alone, 1930-1939; photo# 8-23 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Isidor Achron alone, 1940-1948; photo# 24-42 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Lea Karina alone
    - Lea Karina alone, photo# 43-53 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Carnegie hall poster, photo# 54 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Isidor Achron and Lea Karina
    - Isidor Achron and Lea Karina, photo# 55-64 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Isidor Achron and others
    - With one other person
      - Achron, Joseph, photo# 65-67 (Box 3, Folder 33)
      - Elman, Mischa, photo# 68 (Box 3, Folder 33)
      - Heifetz, Jascha, photo# 69-71 (Box 3, Folder 33)
      - Hudson, Stephen, photo# 72 (Box 3, Folder 33)
      - Menuhin, Yehudi, photo# 73 (Box 3, Folder 33)
      - Wingate, Arlene, photo# 74-78 (Box 3, Folder 33)
      - Unidentified, photo# 79-80 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Groups
      - Isidor Achron, Mrs. Achron, Isidor Achron's sister[?], photo# 81 (Box 3, Folder 34)
      - Jascha Heifetz, unidentified, Isidor Achron., photo# 82 (Box 3, Folder 34)
      - Isidor Achron, unidentified, unidentified, Jascha Heifetz, unidentified., photo# 83 (Box 3, Folder 34)
      - Composition class, Isidor Achron handing score to Alexander Glazunov, Wanda Landowska seated to their right, St. Petersburg., photo# 84-86 (Box 3, Folder 34)
      - Jascha Heifetz, Dick Barthelmess Isidor Achron., photo# 87 (Box 3, Folder 34)
      - Isidor Achron, Dick Barthelmess, Jascha Heifetz, unidentified., photo# 88 (Box 3, Folder 34)
      - Jascha Heifetz, Barbara Kent, Isidor Achron., photo# 89 (Box 3, Folder 34)
      - Unidentified audience, Isidor Achron at piano., photo# 90-91 (Box 3, Folder 34)
      - Robertson, Pierre Luboschitz, Isidor Achron, Erne Balogle., photo# 92 (Box 3, Folder 34)
      - Isidor Achron, Lea Karina, Jascha Heifetz, and others., photo# 93-95 (Box 3, Folder 34)
      - Isidor Achron (2nd row, 3rd from right), Jascha Heifetz (2nd row, 5th from right), and others., photo# 96 (Box 3, Folder 34)
      - Isidor Achron at stock exchange dinner., photo# 97 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Lea Karina and others
    - With one other person
      - Lady Leslie Doverdale, Lea Karina., photo# 98 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Groups
      - Lea Karina, unidentified orchestra., photo# 99-103 (Box 3, Folder 35)
      - Lea Karina, Merchants Marines., photo# 104 (Box 3, Folder 35)
      - Lea Karina (3rd from left, 2nd row), on the set of "To Tell The Truth"., photo# 105 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Isidor Achron, Lea Karina, and others
    - Lea Karina, Isidor Achron, Lucille Sylvester., photo# 106 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Others
    - Achron, Joseph, photo# 107-114 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Achron, Mrs.: mother of Isidor Achron, photo# 115 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Auer, Leopold, photo# 116-117 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Auer, Leopold, photo# 114 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Barthelmess, Richard and Jessica, photo# 118 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Barthelmess, Richard, photo# 119 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Castelnuovo-Tedesco, Mario, photo# 120 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Chaliapin, Fyodor, photo# 121 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Dietrich, Marlene, photo# 119 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Fink, Hyman, photo# 119 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Gabrilovitsch, Ossip, photo# 114 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Heifetz, Jascha, photo# 122-124 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Heifetz, Jascha, photo# 114 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Heifetz, Jascha: child of, photo# 125 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Heifetz, Josepha, photo# 126 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Hofmann, Josef, photo# 114 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Hoover, Herbert, photo# 127 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Hoover, Lou Henry, photo# 128 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - King, Suzanne, photo# 129 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Klemetti, Prof., photo# 130-132 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Klemperer, Otto, photo# 113 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Menuhin, Yehudi, photo# 133 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Menuhin, Yehudi: children of, photo# 134 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Polacco, Giorgio, photo# 135 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Rachmaninoff, Sergei, photo# 114 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Stasevitsch, photo# 114 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Vidor, Florence, photo# 136 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Waldner, Baronen de: daughter of, photo# 137 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Zimbalist, Efrem, photo# 114 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Unidentified, photo# 138-146 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Isidor Achron Photo Album, 56 p. (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Programs and Clippings, Series IV
  - Programs
    - Isidor Achron and Lea Karina, 1930-1939; 1 item (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Isidor Achron and Lea Karina, 1940-1948; 7 items (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Isidor Achron alone, 1930-1939; 9 items (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Isidor Achron alone, 1940-1948; 5 items (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Lea Karina alone, 1930-1939; 3 items (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Lea Karina alone, 1940-1949; 10 items (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Coronation, England, 1937; 1 item (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Elman, Mischa, 1948; 2 items (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Clippings
    - Isidor Achron and Lea Karina, 1934-1939; 7 items (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Isidor Achron and Lea Karina, 1941-1948; 6 items (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Isidor Achron and Lea Karina, no date; 2 items (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Isidor Achron and Lea Karina, 1939 Jul. 16; 1 item (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Isidor Achron and Lea Karina, 1942-1948; 8 items (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Isidor Achron and Lea Karina, no date; 1 item (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Isidor Achron and Lea Karina, 1933-1937; 39 items (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Isidor Achron and Lea Karina, 1941-1947; 17 items (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Isidor Achron and Lea Karina, 1962 Mar. 21; 1 item (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Isidor Achron and Lea Karina, 1989 Mar. 22; 1 item (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Isidor Achron and Lea Karina, no date; 33 items (Box 4, Folder 42)
- Legal Documents, Series V
  - Performances: contracts and correspondence, 1940-1947; 14 items (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - ASCAP: contracts and correspondence, 1941-1975; 8 items (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Copyright contracts, 1935-1943; 25 items (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Copyright seal [3 x 5 cards], 1935-1937; 10 items (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Copyright correspondence, 1936-1971; 12 items (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Music publishers: contracts and correspondence
    - Chappell & Co., Ltd., 1937-1964; 6 items (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Carl Fischer, Inc., 1934-1978; 9 items (Box 4, Folder 46)
- Publicity and Biographical Material, Series VI
  - Brochures with bio and reviews, 1933-1948; 8 items (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Published bios from music trade publications., 1941-1962; 12 items (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Awards
    - United Seamen's Service, Inc., no date; 2 items (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - ASCAP membership election, Isidor Achron, 1941 Jul. 17; 1 item (Box 4, Folder 49)
- Miscellaneous, Series VII
  - Lyrics, membership cards, articles, brochures, menus, seating diagrams, invitations, lists., 53 items (Box 4, Folder 50)
- Additional Materials re Jascha Heifetz, Series VII
  - Clippings
    - [Wisdom magazine], 1956 June; 1 item (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - [Life Magazine], 1969 Oct. 31; 1 item (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - 1970-1977, 4 items (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - 1980 Jan. 31, 1 item (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - no date, 4 items (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Programs [with Isidor Achron], menus, caricature [with Isidor Achron], 13 items (Box 4, Folder 42)
- Additional Materials re Hildegarde, Series IX
  - Music
    - [Darling, je vous aime beaucoup] Darling, je vous aime beaucoup / Ana Sosenko -- New York: Chappell, 1936., Sosenko, Anna; 1 score (3 p.); 31 cm. (Box 4, Folder 53)
      Plate no. C-656-3.
  - Correspondence
    - Karina, Lea, 1958-1988; 14 items (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Photographs
    - Hildegarde alone
      - Hildegarde alone, 1948-1949; photo# H1-2 (Box 4, Folder 55)
      - Hildegarde alone, 1954-1956; photo# H3-13 (Box 4, Folder 55)
      - Hildegarde alone, 1965-1966; photo# H14-15 (Box 4, Folder 55)
      - Hildegarde alone, 1970 Nov. 1; photo# H16 (Box 4, Folder 55)
      - Hildegarde alone, no date; photo# H17-21 (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Hildegarde with one other person
      - Anna?, 1948; photo# H22 (Box 4, Folder 56)
      - Karina, Lea, 1952-1958; photo# H23-26 (Box 4, Folder 56)
      - Karina, Lea, no date; photo# H27-28 (Box 4, Folder 56)
      - Mary Martin, no date; photo# H29 (Box 4, Folder 56)
      - Unidentified, no date; photo# H30-31 (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Hildegarde and Group
      - Hildegarde (1st row, 2nd from left), Lea Karina (far right), 13 unidentified., photo# H32-34 (Box 4, Folder 55)
      - Harry S. Truman, Hildegarde, unidentified, Bess Truman., photo# H35 (Box 4, Folder 55)
      - Lea Karina (2nd from right), Hildegarde (3rd from right), 9 unidentified., photo# H36 (Box 4, Folder 55)
      - Hildegarde (2nd from right), 5 unidentified., photo# H37 (Box 4, Folder 55)
      - Hildegarde (center), 6 unidentified., photo# H38 (Box 4, Folder 55)
      - Lea Karina, Hildegarde, 3 unidentified., photo# H39 (Box 4, Folder 56)
      - Honey?, Hildegarde's mother, Hildegarde., photo# H40 (Box 4, Folder 56)
      - Hildegarde, 3 unidentified., photo# H41 (Box 4, Folder 56)
      - unidentified, Hildegarde, Lea Karina, unidentified., photo# H42 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Clippings
    - 1960-1969, 12 items (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - 1970-1974, 5 items (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - no date, 13 items (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Programs, publicity material, drawings., 6 items (Box 4, Folder 58)
- Sound Recordings, Series X
  All sound recordings in the Isidor Achron Papers have been transferred to Yale Collection of Historical Sound Recordings and a separate inventory prepared.